Rodrigo Abbás

□ rodrigoabbas@gmail.com

Tucumán, Argentina

Professional Summary

Enthusiastic and highly skilled Full Stack Software Developer with +5 years on software industry, 4+ years developing web applications, always providing excellent quality results and maintaining skills up-to-date. Strongly committed to team environment dynamics, with excellent problem-solving and debugging skills and a great willingness to learn.

Work Experience

SMART FLOW - Full Stack Software Engineer Dublin, Ireland 03/2019 - Present

- Creating and designing technical strategies for products and features. Analyzing and implementing technological needs as well as its R&D.
- Designing, providing software solutions and maintaining applications and functionalities for managing IoT devices mainly in C# and JavaScript.
- Developing tools for testing and debugging applications and devices.
- Structuring and working on server and cloud services, products and databases architecture.

Safi Analytics - Full Stack Software Developer San Francisco, CA 02/2018 - 10/2018

- Designed and developed responsive Vue JS front-end to show real-time IoT data with different useful features.
- Developed several Node JS microservices to handle and process all incoming data and to support each feature.
- Designed and implemented SQL/NoSQL databases.
- Trained the new team members and staff.

Sovos - Full Stack Software Developer Tucumán, Argentina 12/2016 - 02/2018

- Designed and built a React-Redux frontend for web application that processes and graphically shows reports for data analysis. Developed several modules and a restful API for its Backend with Node JS.
- Maintained and added several features to an existing web application, working with HTML, CSS and PHP. Simultaneously, migrated its front-end to a React-Redux architecture.
- Provided training for new/other teams members.

Freelancer - Software Developer Tucumán, Argentina 10/2015 - 12/2016

 Provided software solutions to small customers. Designed and developed management application (keeping track of sales, suppliers, inventory and additional information) with different technologies.

+5493816164583

rodrigoabb.github.io/bio

Skills

Frontend

- JavaScript
- Vue JS/ React JS
- HTML & CSS
- Vuex / Redux
- jQuery
- UX & UI

Backend

- Node JS
- C# / .NET
- SQL / NoSQL
- Java
- API Design
- PHP

Frameworks / Tools/ Utilities

- GIT
- Docker
- Sequelize
- GraphQL
- Mocha / Chai
- Jasmine / Jest
- CI/CD
- Cloud Computing

Others

- Software Design Web Development
- Database Design Agile Methodologies
- Test & Debug
- Documentation

Projects

mOsc - Tucumán, Argentina 08/2016 - 04/2017

- · Designed and built an oscilloscope for Mobile Devices, using CIAA platform.
- Implemented Android UI, multiple functionalities and integration.
- · Created workflow system and communication protocol.

Education

Universidad Nacional De Tucumán

- Tucumán, Argentina

Bachelor of Engineering:

Computer Engineering

• Graduated on 06/2017

Languages

• Spanish: Native • English: Fluent